Guide to the Hartwell Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Correspondence: General, 1852-1969; Series II
  Correspondence written and received by members of the Hartwell family appears in chronological order by generation. If the individual Hartwell has material in both categories, letters they wrote appear first, followed by letters received. Correspondence of the second generation is arranged alphabetically. That of the third generation is in chronological order, with the exception of letters written by A. Frank Ufford which appear alphabetically. The material of A. Frank Ufford includes "General Letters", which are newsletters, usually mimeographed or printed, and addressed to a large readership (i.e., "Dear Home Friends"). One letter from a Hartwell relative, Robert G. Edwards, appears in the final folder. Correspondence of the second generation is arranged alphabetically. That of the third generation is in chronological order, with the exception of letters written by A. Frank Ufford which appear alphabetically. The material of A. Frank Ufford includes "General Letters", which are newsletters, usually mimeographed or printed, and addressed to a large readership (i.e., "Dear Home Friends"). One letter from a Hartwell relative, Robert G. Edwards, appears in the final folder.
  - ABH to General Correspondents, 1894, 1920-1926 (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - ABH to General Correspondents, 1931-1937 (Box 7, Folder 119)
  - ABH to General Correspondents, 1938-1939 (Box 7, Folder 120)
  - ABH to General Correspondents, 1940, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 121)
  - ABH: Corres. Rec'd., 1894, 1901, 1913, 1942, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 122)
  - ABH: Corres. Rec'd., 1950, 1952, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 123)
  - ABH from Illegible Signature, "C"., 1896, 1922, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 124)
  - ABH to "Mrs. Thompson", 1955 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - ABH from Sears, Effie J., 1897 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Graves, J., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Moon, L., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - ABH from Murray, Katie, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Goddard, F,W., 1948 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Lois, Todd, Pearl, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - ABH from Courtney, Hugh, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Cauthen, Baker J., 1961 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - AFU to Betty and Herb, 1939-1948 (Box 7, Folder 125)
  - AFU to Bixby, Flanders, Franklin, Fridell, 1911, 1914, 1949, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 126)
  - AFU to Decker, J.W., 1930-1938 (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - AFU to Decker, J.W., 1939 (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - AFU to Decker, J.W., 1940 (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - AFU to Decker, J.W., 1941 (Box 7, Folder 130)
  - AFU to Goodwin, Grover, Haggard, Howard Schaefer, 1911, 1938, 1939, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - AFU: "General Letters", 1908-1934 (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - AFU: "General Letters", 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 133)
  - AFU: "General Letters", 1940-1947 (Box 7, Folder 134)
  - LHU to Hill, Eugene, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Sherman, Harold and Martha, 1973 Sept 19 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Sherman, Harold, 1973 Dec 7 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - LHU from Hill, Eugene, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - LHU: General letters, 1927, 1952, 1961, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - AFU to "Viola", 1927 Feb 7, Feb 15 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - AFU to "Dr. Proctor", 1927 Feb 15, Feb 17 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - AFU to "Mr. Lipphard,", 1927 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Ayres, W.S., 1935 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - fragment, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - AFU to Fridell, E.A., 1951 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - "Leonard", n.d. (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - AFU: General letters, 1930-1948 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - AFU: Corres. Rec'd., 1934-1952, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd., 1929-1939 (Box 7, Folder 135)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd., 1940-1945 (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd., 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 137)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd., 1949 Feb-May (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd., 1949 Jun-Nov (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd., 1950 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd., 1951-1959 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd. - written in Chinese, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd., 1961-1969 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - AFU-LHU: Corres. Rec'd., 1915-1952, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - AFU-LHU: Misc. Corres., 1921, 1938, 1939, 1950, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - ABH-LHU from Crosby, Amy; Craig, J. Kirkwood and Gertrude (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - LHU to Helen, Edith, Helen and Charlotte, 1926, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - LHU: Corres. rec'd., 1927, 1934, 1935, 1941, 1943, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - LHU: Corres. rec'd., 1947, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - LHU: Corres. rec'd., 1952 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - LHU: Corres. rec'd., 1953-1959 (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - LHU: Corres. rec'd., 1960-1969. (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - LHU: Corres. rec'd., 1970-1975, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - RGE to William Meade Addison, introducing JBH, James B. Taylor, 1857, 1858 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - JBH to Graves, R.H., 1866, 1867 (Box 8, Folder 147)
  - JBH from Broaddus, M.E., Burton, G.W., 1868-1874 (Box 8, Folder 148)
  - JBH from Chase, G.W., Crawford, M.F. Crawford, T.P., Crawford, T.R. to illegible signature, 1852, 1864, 1870-1874 (Box 8, Folder 149)
  - JBH from Eckard, L.G., Egan, B.T., Elford, G.E., 1857, 1870, 1871 (Box 8, Folder 150)
  - JBH from Goodenough, A., Graves, R.H., 1861, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 151)
  - JBH from Hayes, John and Corbett, Hunter, 1903 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - JBH from Jackson, R.S., Lambuth (J.W.?), 1864, 1870 (Box 8, Folder 152)
  - Laughton, R., 1874, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 152)
  - JBH, CWNH, ABH from Luce, Henry W., 1902 (Box 8, Folder 153)
  - JBH from Mary, Mollie L., Morrison, Mary E., 1853, 1870, 1873 (Box 8, Folder 154)
  - JBH from Nevins, Helen S.C., Sandford, E., 1870 (Box 8, Folder 155)
  - JBH from Taylor, James B., 1856 (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - JBH from Taylor, James B., 1857 (Box 8, Folder 157)
  - JBH from Taylor, James B: with note from RGE, 1858 (Box 8, Folder 158)
  - JBH from Taylor, James B., 1859 (Box 8, Folder 159)
  - JBH from Taylor, James B., 1860, 1864, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 160)
  - JBH from Taylor, James B., 1870, 1871 (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - JBH from Thayer, William, Williams, N.B., Yates, Matthew, Yates, Matthew to Graves, James, 1866, 1870, 1871, 1875 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - JBH from Illegible Signatures, 1858, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Corres. in Chinese: to JBH - 3 letters of condolence; to EJH - 1 Get Well message, 1870 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - EJH to "Mrs. L.", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - EJH from Desmering, (F.?), Fay, L. Mary, Murrow, J.S., Parks, T.G., Richardson, Ruth, 1857- 1869 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - EJH from Crawford, M.F., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - EJH from DeLoache, E.S., 1858-1859 (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - DJH from DeLoache, E.S., DeLoache, E.S. to "Father, Mother, and sister", 1860-1862, 1865 (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - EJH from DeLoache, E.S., JBH from DeLoache, J. (same letter), 1869 (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - EJH from DeLoache, J., 1859, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - EJH and JBH from DeLoache, J., 1860 (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - EJH and JBH from DeLoache, J., 1865, 1867 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - EJH from (DeLoache?), Leila, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 174)
  - EJH from Hunt, Lizzie R.C. ("Peg")(Hunt?), "Lizzie C." to Mrs. Wright, Hunt, Leonard, (1862?), 1867, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 175)
  - EJH from (Wright, Ellen?), 1860, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 176)
  - JJH from Chester, Dr. and Mrs., Nevins, Helen S.C., no signature, 1870, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 177)
  - CWNH from "B." (Box 8, Folder 178)
  - CWNH from Parry, Frank, 1902 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - "Mrs. Hartwell" from (Nevins, Helen S.C.) illegible signature, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 179)
  - Corres. (fragments and unsigned), 1926, 1947, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Misc. Corres. to/from other than Hartwell Family, 1897, 1910, 1915, 1934, 1941, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 59)
- Writings, 1852-1953; Series III
  This series contains a variety of material, including early sermons attributed to Jesse B. Hartwell, Sr. The locations, dates, and sometimes occasions, of the sermons are noted. Two possible essays are the only writings of J. Boardman Hartwell. The material of A. Frank Ufford consists of addresses, various manuscripts, articles, notes, and notebooks. Private notebooks, which are a combination of scrapbooks, letter books, and diaries, are the main writings of Anna B. Hartwell. An 1887 travel account by an unknown author is located in the folder 89 of this series. All contents are arranged chronologically according to the author's generation.
  - Attributed to Jesse B. Hartwell, Sr.
    - (Essays?): "Christ Died No. II"; "Matthew 5:32", n.d. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Sermons: "Gen. 7:1", 1852 Jan 30 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "Rom. 4:5", 1852 May 28 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "Acts 16:30", 1852 Aug 15 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Sermons: "I Cor 1:18", 1852 Aug 22 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Heb. 4:9 Mrs. Graves Funeral" and note, 1852 Oct 26 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Rom 1:16", 1852 Dec 5 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Sermons: "Lu. 15:10", 1853 Mar 27 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Titus 3: 5 ", 1853 Apr 17 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Titus 3:14", 1853 May 8 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Sermons: "Mat. 5:14, 15, 16'', 1853 Oct 16 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "I Cor. 13:13", 1853 Nov 6 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Sermons: "Mat. 21:22 Prayer", 1854 Mar 5 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "Lu. 24:26 Sufferings of Christ", 1854 Jul 9 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "I Tim. 1:15 A Faithful saying", 1854 Jul 16 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Sermons: "Ma. 10:17-22 What shall I do", 1854 Aug 27 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Prov. 1:20-32 Calls of God", 1854 Sep 24 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Luke 13-24 Strive to enter", 1854 Nov 26 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Sermons: "I Cor. 6:19, 20 Bought with a Price", 1854 Feb 12 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "Heb. 3:7-11 Today - harden", 1854 Jun 11 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "I John 3:23 Believe", 1854 Aug 13 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Sermons: "I Pet. 2:21 Christ suffered for us", 1855 Feb 11 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "John 5:6 Wilt thou be made whole?", 1855 Apr 8 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "Acts 20:21 Repentance", 1855 Apr 22 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Sermons: "Mark 6:12 Repentance", 1855 May 21 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Mat. 26:24 "Punishment", 1855 Jul 8 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "Heb. 10:31 Fearful to fall" (used for funerals), 1855 Jul 28 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Sermons: "I Thess. 5:17 Pray without Ceasing", 1855 Jul 29 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - "I Pet. 4:17, 18 Righteous and Wicked Where?", 1855 Dec 9 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Sermons: "John 3:36 Life and death", 1856 May 18 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - "Romans 8:1 No Condemnation", 1856 Jul 20 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - "Lam. 3:40"', 1856 Oct 20 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Sermons: ''2 Cor. 5:20 Be reconciled to God", 1857 Jun 14 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - "I Cor. 3:6-8 God gives the Increase", 1857 Jun 28 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - "Lu. 14:16-24 Parable of the Supper", 1857 Aug 16 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Sermons: "Acts 17:30, 31 God says, Repent", 1857 Aug 23 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - "2 Pet. 3:17, 18 Beware, lest Grow", 1857 Oct 28 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - "I Cor. 2:2 J.C. crucified", 1857 Nov 1 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Sermons: "Heb. 2:3 The great Salvation", 1858 Jan 17 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Attributed to J. Boardman Hartwell
    - (Essays?): "Time", no title, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - A. Frank Ufford
    - AFU (?): Narrative- Incomplete account of sailing on the "President Coolidge" to the USA, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - AFU: Notes from a binder (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - AFU: Notes, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - AFU: Notes, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - AFU: Sermon Notes and Outlines, 1928-1951 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - AFU: Sermon Notes and Outline, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - AFU (?): Sketches- "Shaohing Pioneer Missionaries", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - AFU: Sketches-"Shanghai to Manila," "Manila to Honolulu," "Honolulu to San Francisco", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - AFU: Sketches-"Shanghai," "On Our Way," "Memorable Days in Japan", n.d. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - AFU: Ms.-"The Burning Bridge" (Rough draft), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - AFU: Article-"The Ufford Pew", 1952 Feb 28 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Addresses: 3 re: "Missionary Policy in the Christian Approach to Communism"- Foreign Missions Conference of North America, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Addresses: "Mission Planning and Policies in the Light of the Far East Conflict" - Foreign Missions Conference; "What Happened in China" - American Baptist Convention; "Christian Witness Under Communist Persecution in China" - American Baptist Convention, 1938, 1953, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Ms.: "The Burning Bridge" - ch. 1-5 by AFU (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Ms.: "The Burning Bridge" - ch. 6-10 by AFU (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Ms.: "The Burning Bridge" - ch. 11-16 by AFU (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Ms.: "China in Retrospect" - pp. 1-25 by K.K. Thompson (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Ms.: "China in Retrospect" - pp. 26-50 by K.K. Thompson (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Ms.: "China in Retrospect" - pp. 51-75 by K.K. Thompson (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Ms.: "China in Retrospect" - pp. 76-87, pp. 1-5 by K.K. Thompson (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Mss: "The Church in Occupied China" 1944, "South China", c. 1946 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Mss: "Communism and Christianity in China" "The Communist Threat to the Chinese Church", 1949, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Mss: "The Future Support of the Church" "The Future Leadership and Support of the Church", c. 1935, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Mss: "East China", "The East China Baptist Mission 1843-1943", "The Evangelistic Field of the East China Mission", 1934, c. 1945, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Mss. re: "Relief Work, Shanghai, Chowtung University, 1937", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Mss: "The Effective Local Application of General Christian Agencies", "Points of Emphasis in Present Day Evangelism", c. 1918, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Mss: "Travel in China", "Travel in Chekiang", "Eight Days Versus Eight Hours - Contrasts in Travel in China", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Mss: "Confucius", "The Jade Monastery and Do Ch'i Deo Church", "The Mokanshan Summer Resort Association", 1947, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Mss: "1944", "East Asia", "A Missionary Postscript", "Things Broken and Unbroken", 1938, 1945, c. 1948 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Mss. re: Rev. T.C. Bau, D.D., William H. Warren, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Mss. re: Shaohing, Hangchow, 1941, 1948, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Mss: complete, single sheets, 1934, 1940, 1943, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Mss: no titles, 1934, 1935, 1937, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Minutes and Reports: "The Advance of Communism in China in Relation to the Church" (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Minutes and Reports: re: East China Mission, 1934, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Minutes and Reports: re: Hangchow, 1946, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Minutes and Reports: re: Shanghai, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Chekiang Shanghai Baptist Convention, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Minutes and Reports: re: Shaohing, 1933, 1936, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Minutes and Reports: re: Principal's Report, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Notes: "Outlying Dependencies" - I "China's New Nationalism" - III "Taoism and Confucianism" - IV "The Action Religions" - V, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Notes: "Buddhism" - VI "The Contacts of Western Christianity with China" - VII "The Beginnings of Protestant Missions" - VIII, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Notes: "Forty years of Missionary Expansion" - IX, "revolution in a Typical Mission" - X "The Mission School" - XI, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Notes: "The Agenda of Cooperation" - XII "Western Medicine in China" - XIII, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Notes: "No. 1 - China and the Chinese" "No. 2 - The Non-Christian Religions of China", "No. 3 - The Contacts of western Christianity with China" (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Notes: "Carver: Christian Missions Facing Today's World", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Notes: "China, the Land and the People" "A New Chapel at San Ka", "Notes in regard to marriage customs in China", 1951, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Notes: "Communism and Christianity in Conflict in China", "The Cloud of Witnesees", "All We Are And All We Have", 1952, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - Notes: "Japan Begins Again", "Brief Resume Of Life in China", "Country Ways and Country Days in Chekiang" (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Notes: from Binders (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Notes: Single Sheets, 1941-1948, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Notebook: Shaohing, China, c. 1934-1942 (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - Notebook: Shaohing, China, c. 1934-1948 (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Printed articles by AFU: "Lovely Mokanshan", "The Night Train to Ningpo, China", "Timely Impressions of a Senior Missionary", "In Remembrance - Percival Rogers Bakeman", 1932, 1933, 1938, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - (Sermons?): "Behold, there was no man there: 2 Kings 7:5", "In one week you will return", "'What Hath God Wrought"', n.d. (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Misc.: "The Future of Christian Missions in China" - a memorandum of informal discussions by China missionaries returning on the USS Breckinridge "Refugee Recordings" by Martha Wilson, 1938, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Misc., 1946-1950, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Anna B. Hartwell
    - Notebook, 1889- 1927 (Box 12, Folder 62)
    - Notebook, 1897 (Box 12, Folder 63)
    - Notebook, 1908 (Box 12, Folder 64)
    - Notebook, 1917-1920 (Box 12, Folder 65)
    - Notebook, c. 1918 (Box 12, Folder 66)
    - Notebook, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 67)
    - Notebook, 1921 (Box 12, Folder 68)
    - Notebook, 1921 (Box 12, Folder 69)
    - Notebook, 1925, 1929, 1935-1936 (Box 12, Folder 70)
    - Notebook, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - Notebook, c. 1927 (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - Notebook, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 73)
    - Notebook, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 74)
    - Notebook, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 75)
    - Notebook, 1933, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 76)
    - Notebook, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 77)
    - Notebook, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 78)
    - Notebook, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 79)
    - Notebook, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 80)
    - Notebook, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 81)
    - Notebook, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 82)
    - Enclosures found in empty notebook, 1944- 1948 (Box 13, Folder 83)
    - Notebooks, c. 1939, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 84)
    - Notebook, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 85)
    - Notebook, (c. 1944?) (Box 13, Folder 86)
    - ABH: Article-"A Christian Dying in a Heathen Land" (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Sketch-"Experience of Anna B. Hartwell Hwanghien, China", n.d. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - ABH: Notebook, 1911 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - ABH (?): Notebook, 1896, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - ABH (?): Notebook, 1921-1924 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Lottie Hartwell Ufford
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - LHU (?): Notebooks, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - LHU (?): Notebooks, 1935, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Writings of others
    - "Christian Experience" by Mrs. Wilson Chen, Misc., n.d. (Box 13, Folder 87)
    - Play Script, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 88)
    - Author Unknown Travel Accounts - " From, N.Y. Sept. 1887 to Tripton, Tulare, Co, Cal Sept. 1887" (Box 13, Folder 89)
    - Report (portion of): "From the Baptist Times", 1934 Aug 9 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Author unknown, outline and narrative: "China, the Land and the People," "In One Week you will Return", 1951, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Helen Nasmith-Schantz (?) - Scrapbook of pictures and poetry (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - "Clarissa Hewey's story of her early days in Kinhwa", 1960 (?) (Box 21, Folder 22)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, Series IV
  The first portion of the series is arranged chronologically according to generation. The second portion consists of the autograph collection of A. Frank Ufford, which is filed alphabetically by writer. A "Complete List of Autographs" is located Box 15 Folder 30. The final portion of the series consists of photographs. Those of the Hartwell Family appear first, followed by general photographs (e.g., "Chinese People", "Chinese Scenes"). Scenes of Shaohing, China appear at the end of the series in the Uffords' photo album.
  - Genealogical Information, incl. corres. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Information re: JBH, Sr. "Address on the Life and Character of Jesse Hartwell, D.D." (elect cop.) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Information re: JBH, Sr. - obituary (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Information re: MFH - "A Missionary Mother" from THE COMMISSION, 1941 Feb (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Information re: JBH - "Chinese in America" from THE BAPTIST UNION; "Report on Obituaries" from MINUTES OF THE STATE CONVENTION, South Carolina (elect cop.), 1898 Feb 26; 1912 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Information re: JBH - Memorial Pamphlet with photographs of the Hartwell Family (in Chinese, with English descriptions) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Biographical Information re: EJH - transcribed from THE RELIGIOUS HERALD, 1870 Sep 1 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Information re: ABH - "In Memoriam" from THE COMMISSION, 1961 Nov (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Biographical Information re: CNH - clippings, article from THE CHRISTIAN INDEX, 1927 Dec 29 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Biographical Information re: AFU - clippings (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - JBH, Sr. - Clippings: "The Examination and Concert at the Female Seminary", no title, 1853 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - JBH - Leases or Deeds; Letter re: Lease or Deed, 1860-1867, n.d.; 1909 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - JBH - Receipts, 1870 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - JBH - "Rules Defining the Relations of the Board of Foreign Missions of the Southern Baptist Convention and its Missionaries" (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - JBH - Scripture References, Poem (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - JBH: Newspaper Clipping re. mission to the Chinese in San Francisco (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - JJH - Pressed Flowers (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - ABH - Clippings (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - ABH - Chinese Language: Bible References, Pamphlet (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - ABH - Invitation, Notes, Poem (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - ABH - Tracts (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - AFU-LHU - articles from MISSIONS, 1927-1931 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - AFU-LHU - bulletins from Foreign Missions Conference of North America; Woman's American Baptist Foreign Mission Society, 1948; 1950-1951 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - AFU-LHU - calling card, paper cuttings, song (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - AFU-LHU - Chinese Language Material (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - AFU-LHU - Financial Material (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - AFU-LHU - Printed Material (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - AFU-LHU - Printed Material re: China Missions (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - AFU-LHU - Travel Pass from the American Consular Service, Shanghai, China, 1925 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - AFU-LHU: Biographical material (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - AFU-LHU: Printed Material (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - LHU - Picture Postcards from "The World in Boston Missionary Exposition" - depicting various religious and ethnic groups, c. 1914 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - LHU: Cards (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - LHU: Medical Report AFU (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Autograph Collection of A. Frank Ufford
    - Explanatory Note by LHU re: Autograph Collection (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - A-B (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - C (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Coolidge, Carrie A. (Mrs. John C.), 1919 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - D-F (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Fish, Hamilton, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - G (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - H (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - J-K (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - L (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - M-O (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - P-R (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - S (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Smith, Alfred E. (copy of letter from AFU to Smith included), 1933 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - T-Y (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Illegible Signatures (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Photographs
    - re: JBH (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - re: JBH, ABH, CNH, and "Tommie" (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - re: CNH (Box 16, Folder 49)